翻译／时间轴 ： Ps
歌曲翻译来自PBU组上的Github，
头2分钟时间轴来自PBU组上预告片时间轴，头13分钟翻译基于组上预告片翻译
不，不可能
No. It can't be.
这不是真的
It isn't true.
嗯，暮光？
Um, Twilight?
暮光！去森灵营地的校车还有10分钟就要走了！
Twilight! The bus for Camp Everfree leaves in ten minutes!
哦，不不不不！
Oh no no no no no!
真不敢相信我睡过头了！
I can't believe I overslept!
我也不信 这不像你的作风
Me, neither. That's not like you.
我知道！
I know!
你不是有一个超级烦人的闹钟吗，就像是
Don't you have a super-annoying alarm clock that goes
没事的 我们帮你打包
It's gonna be fine. We'll help you pack.
我们可是待在森林里
We're gonna be out in the woods.
她怎么会需要这个？
When's she gonna need that?
如果想玩得开心的话
If we were going to the moon,
我必须坚持要她带一件晚礼服
I'd insist she'd pack an evening gown.
指不定就用上了呢，亲爱的
One never knows, darling.
让我先换件衣服
Let me just get changed.
午夜闪闪？！
Midnight Sparkle?!
这怎么可能？
How is this possible?
余晖烁烁帮助我在友谊大赛中打败了你！
Sunset Shimmer helped me defeat you at the Friendship Games!
你和你的朋友永远也不可能真正打败我！
You and your friends can never truly defeat me!
午夜闪闪就是你的一部分！
Midnight Sparkle's a part of you!
我会一直在你内心的阴暗处潜伏！
I'll always be there waiting in the darkest shadows of your mind!
我会回来的，暮光！
I'll be back, Twilight!
并且这次，我不得到所有的魔力誓不罢休！
And this time, I won't stop 'til I have all the magic!
不！停下！
No!STOP!
暮光，醒醒了！
Twilight, wake up!
我们不能停，傻瓜！
We can't stop, silly!
我们还没到站！
We're not there yet!
嘿，你没事吧？
Hey, are you okay?
恩，没事。
Heh. I'm fine.
我们会玩得很高兴的！
We are gonna have so much fun!
我们要烤棉花糖然后吃棉花糖
We're gonna roast marshmallows and eat marshmallows
而且还要枕着棉花糖睡觉！
and sleep on marshmallow pillows!
呃，我们最好别这么玩
Yeah, probably not gonna do that.
我怕就你不想咯！
Maybe you're not!
注意，同学们
Attention, students,
我们快到了
we're almost there.
不过在此之前
But before we arrive,
我们想说
we just wanted to say
能看到你们筹足资金进行这次班级
how proud we are of you for raising enough money
野外旅游我们很骄傲
to go on this class field trip.
我们这个年纪时
When we were your age,
在这片森林里留下了不少美好的回忆
we made some of our favorite memories in this woods,
相信你们也会的
and we're sure you will too.
现在大家都很激动吧！
Now who's excited for Camp Everfree?!
你想随时光流逝还是驻于历史？
Will you be lost by time or be part of history?
你想流芳一世或是隐于神秘里？
Will your story be told or remain a mystery?
他们会不会，传唱你走过的路？
Will they sing your song, telling all that you have done?
选择正当时，只有你能成为你
Time to make your choice, only you can be the one
哦-哦-----------哇哦
Oh-oh-oh-oh-whoa
当你进入这森灵的传说里！
As you join in the Legend of Everfree! (Hey!)
哦-哦-----------哇哦
Oh-oh-oh-oh-whoa
当你加入这森灵的传说里！
As you join in the Legend of Everfree!
嘿！嘿！嘿！
Hey! Hey! Hey!
时间如流水清风，你怎么展飞如鹏？
Will you do something great with the time that you have here?
恐慌于心底盘踞，你怎么一鸣而起？
Will you make your mark, will you conquer what you fear?
当你归来时，所有人都会看见
And when you go back home, everybody there will see
你活跃在那森灵的传说里！
You were part of the Legend of Everfree!
哦-哦-----------哇哦
Oh-oh-oh-oh-whoa
当你进入这森灵的传说里（嘿！）
As you join in the Legend of Everfree! (Hey!)
哦-哦-----------哇哦
Oh-oh-oh-oh-whoa
当你进入这森灵的传说里！
As you join in the Legend of Everfree! (Hey!)
你能否赢得殊荣华丽？
Will you find your greatest glory?
你能否闪耀飞落天际？
Will you be a falling star?
在这里学习自然智慧
Here to learn what nature teaches
在这里追寻你的足迹
Here to learn more who you are
你想随时光逝去还是驻于历史？
Will you be lost by time or be part of history?
你想流芳一世或是隐于神秘里
Will your story be told or remain a mystery?
当你归来时，所有人都会看见
And when you go back home, everybody there will see
你活跃在那森灵的传说里！
You were part of the Legend of Everfree!
哦-哦-----------哇哦
Oh-oh-oh-oh-whoa
当你进入到森灵的传说里！（嘿！）
As you join in the Legend of Everfree! (Hey!)
哦-哦———————————哇哦
Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh
当你进入到森灵的传说里！
As you join in the Legend of Everfree!
嘿！
Hey!
森灵营地不是很漂亮吗？
Isn't Camp Everfree just beautiful?
我等不及我们的第一次野外徒步了
I can't wait until we have our first nature walk.
我一直想来一次野外徒步来着
I definitely wanna go on one of those.
你也想闻闻哪些可爱的森林生物吗？
You wanna smell the adorable woodland creatures, too?
是啊！尤其是松鼠！
Yeah! Specifically squirrels!
不过我其实更想追追它们呢！
More specifically, so I can chase 'em!
我只想来干些活
I'm just lookin' forward to roughin' it.
我要搭我自己的庇护所
I'm gonna make my own shelter,
搜寻食物……
forage for food...
呃，你知道他们会在帐篷里向我们提供食物的，对吗？
Uh, you know they provide us with food in tents, right?
是！但我还是想去找
Yep! Still gonna forage though.
我就想放松放松
I'm just after some R&R.
这一年里出的事都快把我压垮了
The past year has all been a bit too much for my taste.
可不是嘛！
I'll say!
我们打败了三只用歌声催眠大家的海妖
We fought three evil sirens who tried to hypnotize everybody with their singing,
一间想赢想疯了的学校
one ridiculously competitive rival school,
还有两名会变身成恶魔的朋友！
and two demon friends!
啊，哈哈，无意冒犯
Uh, heh heh, no offense.
没关系
None taken.
你会习惯的
You'll get used to it.
对
Yep.
坎高这地方和魔法总是扯不开关系
Canterlot High has become a regular magic magnet.
能到一个不用担心这些破事的地方
Gonna be nice gettin' away to a place
真是太好了
where we don't have to worry 'bout that kinda stuff.
这个给你，暮光
Here ya go, Twilight.
谢了
Thanks.
你是阿绅，对吧？
It's Flash, right?
对，是我！
Yup, that's me!
而且你是你
And you're you.
并且我们不太了解对方
And we don't know each other very well.
很酷的故事，兄弟
Cool story, bro.
恩，那么……失陪了
Right. I guess I'll... see you around.
你还记得那个和你长得一模一样
You know how there's that girl who looks just like you
住在平行世界
and she's here but lives in another dimension
还当着小马公主的女生吗
and she's a pony princess?
嗯哈
Uh-huh.
阿绅有点对她……有意思
Flash kinda had a... thing for her.
噢
Oh.
嗨，大家！
Hey, everyone!
如果你们能朝庭院这边看过来，可就再好不过了！
If you could start heading to the courtyard, that'd be rad!
是时候开始史上最棒的露营周了！
It's time to start the best week of camp ever!
大家好！
Hi, everyone!
欢迎来到森灵营地！
Welcome to Camp Everfree!
我是嘉兰金菊，你们的营地向导！
I'm Gloriosa Daisy, your camp director!
就把我当做你们亲切和蔼的营地和森林里的向导吧
Think of me as your friendly camp and nature guide.
这是我哥哥，云杉棕木！
And this is my brother, Timber Spruce!
把我当成那种酷酷的
Think of me as that awesome guy...
喜欢干好玩的事情的那种人
who should always be invited to fun things.
我们希望你们能玩得开心
We aim to please,
所以在进行帐篷的人员分配之前
so before we hand out our tent assignments,
我们也想听听你们的意见
we'd like to hear from all of you.
在这里，你们想干什么都可以！
You're free to do whatever you like here!
啊，但是不能跑到采石场那边去
Uh, except hike near the rock quarry.
这是规定
That's off limits.
对，不过除此之外，建议你们随便提
Yes, but otherwise, your options are wide open.
那么对你们来说什么样的活动才是最棒露营周该有的？
So what activities will make this the very best week of your lives ever?
嗷！攀岩！
Ooh! Rock climbing!
好！
Done!
射箭！
Archery!
肯定的！
Of course!
绳球！
Tetherball!
当然会有！
Naturally!
云宝，我知道你很兴奋
Rainbow, I know you're excited,
但也得给别人一个说话的机会吧
but maybe give somebody else a chance to make a suggestion.
美术和手工！
Arts and crafts!
我妈妈……需要新的厨房手套
My mom... needs new pot holders.
我会提供织布机！
I'll supply the looms!
装饰饼干！
Cookie decorating!
我能做出超棒的甜曲奇。
I do make a mean sugar cookie.
晨间漫步？
Early morning nature walks?
那每个人都发一根手杖！
With walking sticks for everyone!
我！哦，呃，时装秀！
Me! Oh, uh, a fashion show!
我要根据时尚潮流
Where I design the most fabulous camp looks
来设计最漂亮的营地风时装
inspired by today's hottest trends
然后让同学们当模特走室外T台！
and have them modeled by my classmates in a gorgeous outdoor setting!
露营传统！
A camp tradition!
我们可没搞过这种活动
We have literally never done that.
你们在这里时有什么事情都可以和我说
I'll be taking requests the rest of the time you're here,
所以如果你们还想做什么别的活动，或者有什么需要，尽管找我
so if there's anything you'd like to do, anything you need, just ask.
但是营地礼物呢？
But what about the camp gift?
那是我最喜欢的森灵营地传统
That was my favorite Camp Everfree tradition.
营地礼物！当然了！
The camp gift! Of course!
蛤？
Really?
对，真的
Yes, really.
啊，我只是想……
Well, I just thought...
那你想错了！
Then you thought wrong!
有人注意到嘉兰和她哥之间有点不对劲吗？
Anyone else picking up on a little tension between Gloriosa and her brother?
呃……
Ehhh...
有点
Little.
每年，营员们一起制作有用的东西
Every year, campers work together to create something useful.
作为给未来营员的礼物
A gift for future campers
为这个目标共同努力
Working toward this common goal is key to forming the strong bonds
that will last well beyond your time here at camp!
是你们之间形成牢固友谊的重要方式
所以这事很重要
Which is why it's so important.
这个露台是去年队伍的礼物
This gazebo was a gift from last year's group.
噢，噢，噢，还有图腾柱和日晷也是由营员们制造的！
Oh, oh, oh, and the totem pole and the sundial were also made by campers!
那日晷是我们那年的礼物！
The sundial was our year's gift!
当年某些人还泼冷水
Even though "some people" thought it was a little impractical,
说日冕晚上不能用来着
since the sundial can't be used at night.
你们看上去是一支非常棒的团队
You all seem like a-a really amazing group.
所以我确信你们肯定能留下些鼓舞人心的东西
So I'm certain you'll come up with something inspiring to leave behind.
说到留下东西
Speaking of leaving things behind,
我们应该给出帐篷的人员分配了
now's the time when we give out tent assignments.
这样你们好放行李
So you can leave your heavy bags behind.
恩，女生们到云杉棕木那里去听他分配
Uh, girls will be getting their assignments from Timber.
小伙子们跟我来
Guys, you're with me.
哦，天啊！嗯……
Oh, boy! Hmm...
耶！我在绿宝石帐篷！
Yay! I'm in the Emerald Tent!
噢，我也是！
Ooh, me, too!
海蓝宝石
Aquamarine.
我也是！
Me, too!
- 哇喔！ - 好呀！
- Woohoo! - Oh, yeah!
我是紫水晶
I got Amethyst.
蓝宝石
Sapphire.
我也是！
Me, too!
我是说，我认为我是，嘿嘿
I mean, I'm assuming I am. Heh heh.
从理论上来说，蓝宝石可不只有蓝色的，嘿嘿
Technically, sapphires aren't just blue. Heh heh.
它们也可以是粉色，紫色，黄色……
They can be pink, purple, yellow...
对，但是它们大多是蓝色
Yeah, but they're mostly blue.
这就是为什么人们用拉丁文 sapphirus 来命名蓝宝石
That's why they're named after the Latin word, sapphirus.
意思是，蓝色
That means, "blue".
知道。不过你知不知道蓝宝石就是少了铬的红宝石？
I know. But did you know that sapphires are just rubies without chromium?
不知道
No.
不过你知不知道蓝宝石帐篷是最好的？
But did you know that Sapphire Tent is the best one?
不知道。为什么？
No. Why's that?
因为有你在
Because you're in it.
噢，我打赌你对所有营员都这么说。
Oh, I bet you say that to all the campers.
不是这样
Not true.
你在红宝石帐篷？哈！那是最差的！
You're in the Ruby Tent? Ha! That's the worst one!
啥鬼！
Ah, man!
开个玩笑，伙计
I'm just jokin', buddy.
红宝石帐篷很棒
The Ruby Tent is great.
它很像蓝宝石，但是有铬
It's like a sapphire, but with chromium.
但红宝石帐篷和珊瑚帐篷太像，怕你分不清
But the Ruby and Coral Tents do look an awful lot alike to the undiscerning eye.
我还是带你过去好了
I better show you where it is.
回见
See ya around.
咋啦？
What?
呵，没嘛事
Heh. Nothin'.
噢！那真可爱！
Ooh! That was adorable!
好了各位
Okay, everyone,
安顿下来吧
go get settled in.
十五分钟后在码头集合
We'll be meeting at the docks in fifteen minutes
学习野营安全规则！
to go over some camp safety rules!
有需要帮忙的就叫我吧！
Let me know if you need anything!
我需要帮忙
I need somethin'.
臭钱！很高兴见到你
Filthy Rich! So nice to see you.
你在这干嘛呢？
What are you doing here?
野营刚刚开始呢！
Camp is just getting started!
只是四处看看风景罢了 嘉兰金菊
Just takin' in the scenery, Gloriosa Daisy.
这很...嗯...令人放松
It's so... hmm... relaxin'.
好吧 你可以在野营结束后继续看风景呀！
Well, you can look around when camp is over!
如果现在你不介意的话.……
Now, if you don't mind...
好吧
Fine.
臭钱他，呃，当年也是营员
Filthy Rich is, uh, an alumni of the camp.
他常喜欢来他留恋的地方转转
He likes to check on his old stomping grounds every now and again.
咱不说他了
But enough about him.
找到你们的帐篷 放好东西
Find your tents and put away your things.
野营的黄金周等着我们呢！
We've got the best week of camp ever to begin!
我完全赞同学习安全规则
I'm all for learning safety rules,
但我更希望能提早开始为
but I do hope I can get started on my designs for the
野营时装秀准备设计
camp fashion show sooner rather than later.
我还是不信你竟然真的说服雏菊办时装秀了
I still can't believe you talked Gloriosa into havin' a fashion show.
我们这可是在丛林腹地啊！
We're in the middle of the woods for cryin' out loud!
粗野一点才好啊！
We're s'posed to be roughin' it!
从雏菊的着装上来看
It's clear from Gloriosa's own wardrobe
她也是欣赏漂亮服饰的类型
that she appreciates a well put together look.
即使我们是在……丛林腹地
Even if we are in the... middle of the woods.
有道理 只要你别给我穿那些稀奇古怪的东西就行
Fair enough. Just as long as you don't put me in one of your fancy pants outfits.
你打算好了，是吧？
Yer gonna, aren't ya?
不
No.
不！别担心
Yes! Don't worry.
给你的衣服绝对符合你的审美观……
It'll absolutely speak to your personal sense of fashion...
刚刚那会儿很奇怪对吧？
That was weird back there, right?
就那家伙，臭钱？
With that guy, Filthy Rich?
我猜是吧
I guess so.
我只是感觉金菊在隐瞒什么
I just have this feeling that Gloriosa's hiding something.
不过她哥人不错啊，对 吧
Her brother is pretty cute, though, huh?
他挺好
He's okay.
现在看看谁在隐瞒了！
Now look who's trying to hide something!
不 才没有！
No, I'm not!
喂 你还好吗？
Hey, you okay?
你刚刚在巴士上看起来吓坏了
You seemed a little freaked out on the bus earlier.
她大概又做了个噩梦吧
Probably had another one of her nightmares.
我很好
I'm fine.
毕竟最近诸事顺心啊
I mean, what do I have to complain about?
我转到坎高这边之后
Ever since I transferred here,
大家都接受我，相处也融洽
everyone from CHS has been really nice and accepting,
即便是我在友谊大赛上做了那些事情
especially considering what happened at the Friendship Games.
那不是你的错
That wasn't your fault.
是严校长引诱你尝试那些魔法
Principal Cinch is the one who encouraged you to try
去帮助水晶预科获取胜利
and use all that magic to win the games for Crystal Prep.
你还没准备好运用那种魔力
You weren't ready to have that kind of power.
但都过去了
But it's over now.
要说有什么集体会原谅你的过错的话
And if there's any group that's gonna forgive you for something that happened in the past,
相信我，就是这
trust me, it's this one.
你们磨蹭什么呢？
You guys comin' or what?
马上来！
Be right there!
我就想擦点防晒霜
I just wanna put on some sunscreen.
明明记得带了来着
Coulda sworn I packed it.
找到啦！
Found it!
你这是……
Did you?
怎么可能？
How is this possible?
难以置信，真是太棒了  太糟了
I can't believe this. It's amazing! terrible!
你说什么呢？真是太棒了
Are you kidding? This is great!
我们以前也马化过，长耳朵，翅膀，尾巴，打友谊大炮
I mean, we've all ponyed up before, gotten the whole ears and wings and tail thing, shot magical rainbow lasers,
但是这种事还没发生过
but nothing like this has ever happened!
你怎么做到的
How did you do it?
我不知道
I don't know!
也许不是我干的
Maybe I didn't?
是她
Maybe it's her?!
谁？
Her who?
没啥，算了
Nothing. Nevermind.
那个，这事我们不说行吗？
Can we just not talk about it?
还有，你也别跟别人说啊
And could you please not bring this whole levitating thing up to the others?
为什么？
Why not?
你也听阿杰说了
You heard Applejack.
这里本来是让大家不用去担心魔法的地方
This is supposed to be the place where everyone can get away from magic.
我不想让她们知道我又带新品种来了
I don't want them to know I brought some crazy new kind with me.
你真的这么想的话我不说就是了
If you really don't want me to, I won't say anything.
真的
I really don't.
好吧，但其实这也不一定是坏事啊
Okay, but this isn't necessarily a bad thing!
我想你还是用手吧
I think you just gotta have to pick it up.
……怎么行啊！
...show up like that!
你刚刚说啥？
What did you say?
我…什么也没说啊
I... didn't say anything.
就是来这里让大家去码头
Just here to make sure everyone was headed over to the docks!
你有什么需要吗？
Did you need something?
没
Nope.
有什么能让这周成为你最棒野营周的事情
Because if there is anything I can do to make this week the best week ever,
告诉我就行
you just let me know.
我行的
I've got this!
谢了，我没事
Thanks, I'm good.
那么爽快的人总是让我有点紧张
People that chipper make me nervous.
绝对要爽翻天啦
This is gonna be so much fun!
你倒不算
I guess not all people.
太美了，不是吗？
Oh, it's beautiful, isn't it?
就像太阳下闪耀的一颗钻石
It looks like a diamond shining in the sun!
这里真好，清新的空气，微风，还有落到你手上的小鸟
It is lovely out here. The fresh air, the cool breeze, the birds that land on your finger.
那种鸟事只会发生在你身上啦
I think that only happens to you.
每天日落之前湖面活动都是开放的
Lake activities are available every day until sunset,
所以想玩独木舟，帆船，帆板，或者游泳，跟我说就好
so if you want to canoe, sail, windsurf or swim, just let me know.
它们最可爱了不是吗？
Aren't they just the cutest?
诶，我知道我有吸引力，但是你这失足也太快了吧
Whoa! I know I'm charming, but you don't have to fall for me.
我也不该嫉妒，对吧？
Guess I can't get too jealous, right?
毕竟那也不是我的暮暮
After all, she isn't my Twilight.
我也没说另一个暮暮是我的啊
Not that the other Twilight was mine!
我们只是…你懂的…
But, we were... you know.
是，我明白
Yeah. I get it.
但你的暮暮是一只小马公主
But if your Twilight is a princess in Equestria,
不想打击你，但是人家基本都得在马国过
hate to break it to you, but that's where she's gonna spend most of her time.
你的意思是我该放弃了？
So you're saying I just need to get over it?
差不多吧
Kinda, yeah.
哎，说得我心痛啊
Ouch! You're not pulling any punches.
我这人平常也不这样，抱歉咯
Not really my style. Sorry.
这个有安全隐患啊
This is a safety hazard.
露营期间我们还是把码头封了吧
I suggest we close down the dock for the remainder of the camp.
我相信不需要关那么久
Oh, I'm sure it won't have to be for the remainder of the camp.
稍微修修就行，我行的
Just needs to be patched up a bit. I've got this!
唔，能行的是我们才对
Huh. Or maybe we do!
要我说，这码头砸了算了
If you ask me, this whole dock needs to go.
我们再修一个，就当营地礼物！
Building a new one could be our camp gift.
自然对我们是有好处的，而且对以后的营员都是一个馈赠
Sure, it would benefit us, but a nice new dock would benefit future campers, too.
真的行吗，工作量很大的
I don't know. It's an awful lot of work.
我不希望你们一直忙着修码头造福社会，没时间玩别的露营活动啊
I wouldn't want you guys to miss out doing other fun camp stuff, because you're so busy building a dock for future campers.
木杉，你说的我们懂，
I hear what you're saying, Timber,
但我们是坎高奇骏团，名声在外
but we're Canterlot Wondercolts! We've got a reputation to uphold!
不留个最赞的营地礼物我们可不走
And there's no way we're gonna leave this place without contributing the most awesome camp gift ever!
我支持阿杰，就修个新码头
I'm with AJ, building a new dock is definitely it!
你们觉得呢？
What do you guys think?
看来木已成舟
Looks like it's settled, then.
看来是啊
Looks like it.
这俩关系真心不对劲
That's some tension alright.
地基可以加固一下
We can reinforce the foundation.
修得又牢又漂亮
make it nice and sturdy.
还可以用木头刻个“森灵营地”的牌子挂上
And we can add a woodcarved sign this is Camp Everfree.
拿几个小盒子装喂鱼和小鸭子的事物
And little boxes with food so you can feed the ducks and fishes.
再加上灯，晚上才能看见
Oh, we'll add lanterns so you can see at night!
真漂亮，而且拿来做我的营地时装秀的T台肯定棒
Oh, it's stunning! And will make an absolutely perfect runway for my camp fashion show!
更重要的是，能停独木舟，喂鱼什么的
Or importantly, it will be a great place for docking canoes and feeding the wildlife.
都差不多，反正一定是波西米亚嬉皮风的好展台
Oh, you say tomato, I say perfect place to showcase glamorous boho-chic stylings.
你们怎么看？
What do you guys think?
工作量很大，但我们可以的
It's going to be a lot of work, but we can do it!
太好了！有大人监督！
Yes! Adult supervision!
锤子不错啊，哪里拿的？
Huh, nice hammer. Where did you get it?
工具箱啊
The toolbox?
不错哦，我的是自己做的
that's cool. I made mine.
用太阳能花园灯来做光源
Making lanterns out of solar-powered garden lights!
木杉，手挺巧啊
Pretty crafty there, Timber!
这算手巧？你该看看我的通心粉艺术
You think that's crafty? You should see my macaroni art.
我可是面条界的毕加索
I'm like the Picasso of noodles.
好了，今天进展神速哦，但是天要黑了
Aright, now! You've made a lot of progress. But it's going to be getting dark soon.
明天有空的时候再继续
We can pick this up tomorrow between our other camp activities.
大家收拾一下，八点钟火堆旁集合，有烤棉花糖和鬼故事
Everyone, get cleaned out, and we'll gather by the fire pit at eight to share s'mores and scary stories!
烤棉花糖！
S'MORES!!!
……当她向自己身下看去
......And that's when she looked down
发现自己紫色袜子配的是紫红裙子
and realized she was wearing purple socks with the burgundy dress!
紫色和紫红啊，同一个色系的啊
Purple and burgundy, darlings! The same color family!
还真吓人啊
That was a terrifying story.
吓得我都不敢听她再讲一遍了
I' m terrified she'll try to tell it again.
咳咳，谁还有鬼故事吗？
Anyone else have a spooky story?
我有个
I have one.
但事先警告你们，先找个朋友抱抱吧
But I'm warning you, you might as well hug a friend now.
会吓死你们哦
That's how scary it is!
天啊
Oh, dear.
是时候给你们讲讲森灵盖娅的传说了
It's time I told you about the legend of Gaia Everfree.
很多年以前，我的曾祖父母来到这片森林
Many years ago my great grandparents came to this forest.
美景之下他们觉得这里做营地一定完美
Seeing its beauty, they decided that it would be the perfect place for a camp.
但是他们开始动工之后
But once they started building
诡异的事情就开始发生了
, strange things started to happen.
一个月黑风高之夜
One pitch-black night, when the wind was howling,
一棵树砸穿他们小屋的屋顶
a tree branch crashed through the roof of their cabin.
他们尖叫着跑出来，却发现一个巨大的生物出现在眼前
They screamed and ran outside, only to see the giant creature rising from the earth.
头发如树根般扭曲
She got wild hair, like the roots of a tree.
牙齿参差可憎
Her mouth had jagged rock teeth
眼睛如一片漆黑的焦油池
and her eyes were pools of black tar.
下身钻石般闪闪发光
But her aura shimmered like diamonds.
所到之处留下一串发光的粉尘
Anywhere she went, she left a trail of gemdust in her wake.
曾祖父母颤抖着问她是何方神圣，有何贵干
Trembling, my great grandparents asked who she was and she wanted.
她用低沉空洞的声音说自己是森灵盖娅
In a deep and hollow voice she told them that her name was Gaia Everfree
统治森林的上古神灵
an ancient spirit who held domain over the forest,
而我的曾祖父母侵犯了她的领地
and that my great grandparent were trespassing on her land.
曾祖父母跪下求她让他们修起这个营地
They begged her to let them stay and build their camp
让别人也有欣赏这里美景的机会
to share this wonderful place with others.
森灵盖娅终于同意了
Gaia Everfree finally agreed,
但警告他们，这里不会一直让他们呆下去
but warned them that they would not be able to keep it forever.
有一天她会回来，将森林收回自己掌中
Some day she will return and reclaim the forest as her own.
所以如果你看见一串发光的粉尘
So if you see a trail of gemdust,
那你就是碰到了
you'll know that it is...
森灵盖娅！
Gaia Everfree!
大家好啊！
Hey, guys!
抱歉，不是故意吓你们的
Sorry, didn't mean to scare you!
那你从灌木里冒出来干什么？
Then why'd you come out of the bushes?
我绕路看了看风景，晚上的森林很漂亮啊
I... took the scenic route, because the forest is beautiful at night.
但是你们没向导的话可别学我，好吗？
But no one else should do it without a guide, okay?
好了各位，可以回帐篷了
Alright, everybody, time to head to you tents.
那个，雏菊姐，你有多的牙刷没？
Oh, hey, Gloriosa. Do you have extra toothbrushes?
我忘带我的了
I forgot mine.
当然有了，我会给你拿一个
Sure do! I'll get one for you.
我怕黑，你有手电筒吗
I'm scared of the dark! Do you have flashlights?
当然有了，我行的
Of course! I got this!
唔……小蝶……！
……Fluttershy?……！
抱歉，斯派克
Sorry, Spike.
我是被那个故事吓到了
I guess that story got to me.
为啥？又不可能是真的
Why? It can't be real.
不清楚哦，森灵盖娅可能是从马国被赶出来的
I don't know. Gaia Everfree some creature that got booted from Equestria and ended up in this world.
海妖就是这个套路
That's what happened with the sirens.
哼，感觉像是木杉编出来吓唬我们的
Eh. Sounded more like something that Timber was making up just to scare us.
至少我希望如此
At least I hope it was.
最怕的就是又跑来个魔法生物毁了我们的露营
Last thing I want is to have camp ruined by some power-crazed magical creature.
这种事情我们是身经百战了，见得多了
Oh, hear-hear. We had to deal with more than our fair share of those.
秋季舞会，音乐节，还有友谊大－
At the Fall Formal, a musical showcase, the Friendship Ga–
啊啊啊，反正最后一切都归于平静了
Well, I mean, you know, everything turned out alright, of course
我有点累了，我先走了
I'm kinda tired. I'm in a turn in.
还是不要提友谊大赛的事情了
Maybe lay off bringing up what happened at the Friendship Games?
我看她还是有点敏感
I think she's still pretty sensitive about it.
我的嘴封好了
Our lips are sealed.
我来了
Here I am!
这边
Over here.
我一直在
I'm always here!
不要
No!
谁来了？出什么事了？
Who's there? What happened?
没什么，抱歉，余晖
Nothing. Sorry, Sunset.
暮暮，我觉得还是出了事了
Uh, Twilight, I think something happened.
都到起床时间了啊
Is it time to get up already?
暮暮，我们真的需要谈谈
Twilight, we really have to talk about this.
不，不需要
No, we don't!
那个，我知道你不情愿
Hey, I know you don't want to,
但我们真的得弄明白你的魔法是怎么回事
but I really think we need to figure out what's going on with your magic.
如果你能学会控制的话
If you could learn to control it–
这就是问题所在，我永远都没法控制
That's just it! I'll never be able to control it!
出什么事了？
What happened?
我不是故意的
I didn't mean to!
我们也没看见，不知道
We didn't see anything, so we don't know what happened.
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
嗯，太诡异了
Yeah. It was so weird.
我们正在湖中间，没风走不动
We were stuck in a middle of the lake with no wind,
然后突然
then all of a sudden BAM!
风大了，我们直接被一路推到了码头上
The wind picked up and we were pushed right into the dock.
会不会是那个盖娅啊？
You don't think it was the spirit, do you?!
不，是我
No, it was me.
神明啊，显出你的真身吧！
Spirit, show yourself!
听从天下无双的崔克茜的召唤！
The Great and Powerful Trixie commands it!
那是什么？
What's that?!
真是的，白做那么多工，都没了
Oh, man! All our hard work! Ruined!
至少鱼儿们挺好
At least the fishes are really well.
看能从水里捞上来点什么，也许还能补救的
Let's salvage what we can out of the water. Maybe we can still fix this?
必须要，森灵营地可少不了我们的T台
We have to try! Camp Everfree needs our runway!
码头
Dock.
啊，码头，我就那意思
Dock, yes, that's what I meant.
这原是小事一筹
It used to be so simple
这世界我原已参透
It was a world I understood
在我不知的那迷雾背后
I didn't know what I didn't know
一切都乐悠悠
And life seemed pretty good
但现在黑恶涌起
But now the darkness rises
在我心 无底深渊里
From somewhere deep inside of me
那魔力握我于掌心
Her power all but takes me
能不能 封印这恶魔 在心底？
Can I keep this midnight from getting free?
如我能沐浴晴岚
If I can stay in the light
解放我自己
I know I'll be free
为完整自我守候
Then I can start to be whole
我会做回自己
I can start to be me
然而我 挣扎 无止息
But instead I am struggling
为我所见之谜
With all that I see
朋友们
And these friends
愿不见我黑暗的心
Mustn't see the midnight in me
那黑暗的心
The midnight in me-ee
愿不见我黑暗的
They mustn't see the midnight in
心~
Meeeee
好多松鼠啊
So many squirrels.
斯派克
Spike?
唉，刚刚我正做美梦呢
Ah! Oh, aw man! I was having the best dream.
等等，美梦可以成真啊
Wait, that dream could be a reality!
别急着追松鼠，你知道暮暮会在哪吗？
Before you run off to chase squirrels, do you have any idea where Twilight could be?
我真的得和她谈谈
I really need to talk to her.
出什么事了？她又让东西到处飞了？
What happened? Did you do that lifting things off the ground again?
问题就在这里，我也不知道是不是她做的
That's just it, I don't know if it was her,
但如果是，那就不能躲躲闪闪的
but if it was, we need to deal with it head on.
我能找到她
I can track her down.
冷静，深呼吸，你不是一个怪物
Keep it together. Deep breaths. You are not a monster.
啊，你好，你在这里干啥呢？
Oh, hi. What are you doing here?
在找你啊
Uh, looking for you.
我就是出来踏青，然后有点迷路了
Oh, I just went on a nature walking, got a little lost.
我带你走吧，这片我很熟悉了
Let me show you the way. I'm kind of an expert on these woods.
我这一辈子都住在这里
I've lived here my whole life.
在营地长大的生活一定很棒吧
That must have been nice. Growing up at a camp.
是，不过也有不好的地方
Yeah, though it has its downsides.
我年轻的时候曾经想要把这里卖了
When I was younger I wish we would sell this place
然后到城里去和普通人一样生活
so we can live in a town like normal people.
真的？
Really?
我才十岁，特别想去商场逛
I was ten. I really wanted to hang out in the mall.
这事我还没跟别人说过
I've never told that to anyone.
你一定跟别人不一样
You must be special.
而且不只是因为头发里插了根树枝
And not just because you have tree branch in your hair.
插了多久了？
How long has that been in there?
也不久，你说话的时候一直有
Not long. Just the whole time we were talking.
你怎么不告诉我啊
Then why didn't you say something?
看来帮暮暮处理魔法的事情可以稍微缓缓
I guess we can help Twilight deal with the magic stuff a little later.
攀岩重在坚持与信任
Rope climbing is all about perseverance and trust.
瑞瑞你要信任阿杰能拉好你
Rarity, you can trust that Applejack will spot you.
对啊，所以不用这么磨磨蹭蹭的
Yeah, so you can totally go faster than you're going.
云宝黛西
Rainbow Dash!
对不起嘛，从来这里开始我就一直想爬了好吧
Sorry. I've been waiting to do this since we got here.
那亲爱的你得再等等了
Well, you have to wait a little longer, darling.
啊，暮暮，你来拉我，我就能上了
Oh, good! Twilight, if you spot me, I can finally go.
我再去拿一副安全带
I'll go get another harness.
我不是很……
I'm not sure–
我得去看看我姐有没有啥需要
I'll better make sure my sister doesn't need anything.
一会见了
See you later.
暮暮，你在这啊
Twilight, there you are!
我终于找到你了
I was looking for you!
刚刚是地震了吗？
Was that an earthquake?
这里不是断层附近啊
We aren't near any fault lines.
谁弄的这些闪闪发光的东西啊
Who left this crystally dusty stuff here?!
我觉得我可以下来了
I-I believe I'd like to come down now!
抱歉，有点卡住了
Sorry, it's a little bit stuck.
阿杰！你干什么呢！
Applejack! What are you doing?!
没出什么事吧？
Is everything okay over there?
我也不知道是怎么了，我拉绳子根本没那么用劲
I don't know what happened. I didn't even pull the rope that hard.
感觉她突然变得和羽毛一样轻了
It's like she was light as a feather all of sudden.
快把我吓死了
I was scared half to death!
不是我的错，让我帮你把安全带取下来吧
It wasn't my fault! Let me help you get your harness out.
不需要，谢谢了
No, thank you!
这到底是怎么了
What in the world just happened?!
天啊，我真的太抱歉了
Oh, dear! I am so sorry!
差不多吧
I think.
刚刚那一下真的是我做出来的？
Did I just do... whatever that was?
应该不是你的错
I don't think it was your fault.
我去给阿杰拿条毛巾
I need to get Applejack towel.
我也去
Me too.
不只是你一个人有新魔法！太棒了！
You're not the only one with a new kind of magic! This is great!
才不棒呢！瑞瑞和阿杰差点弄伤对方了
No, it's not! Rarity and Applejack could have really hurt each other!
为什么会这样，我不－
Why is this happening? I don't–
你们好啊
Hi, girls!
有什么需要吗
Anything I can do for you?
阿杰刚刚掉湖里去了
Uh, Applejack just fallen to the lake!
这可不好
Oh, no!
该给她拿温毛巾，干衣服，还有热可可！
She's gonna need warm towels, dry clothes, oh, and a hot cocoa!
我行的
I've got this!
小蝶？
Fluttershy?
出什么事了？
What happened?!
就是我们刚刚在装饰曲奇然后－
You know, we were just decorating cookies and–
然后我就说‘再来点闪粉！再来点闪粉！’
And I was all "You need more sprinkles! And you need more sprinkles!"
标准的萍琪套路
So, standard Pinkie Pie stuff.
我把闪粉给小蝶丢过去的时候
I was just tossing sprinkles to Fluttershy,
它们突然发粉光，然后就爆炸啦
when all of a sudden they glowed pink and exploded!
之前也是这个样子！
Just like that, only earlier!
好吧－那你接下来的一段时间还是不要乱碰东西好了？
Oookaay, why don't you lay off touching stuff for a while?
不好，我们真得把这里弄干净
Oh, dear. We really should clean all of this up.
能帮帮我吗
Can someone help me out?
谢谢了，鸟先生
Thank you, mister bird.
当然能给你弄点－
Why, of course I can get you little something to–
你刚刚…说话了？
Did you just... talk?
可是我不会说鸟语啊
But I don't speak chirp.
不知道是不是只有你的话我听得懂
I don't know if you're the only bird I can understand.
不要！不要把你的朋友们叫过来
Oh, no! Please don't call for your friends.
也很高兴见到你们
It's nice to meet all of you, too.
你刚刚是跟鸟搭上话了？
Were you just talking to the birds?
是啊？
Um, yes?
你跟她们说了刚刚的事情没有？
Did you tell them what happened?
简直疯了
So crazy!
我把瑞瑞一下就拉到了攀岩墙顶上
I hoisted Rarity up the wall climbing wall like it was nothing!
好像力气比平常大多了
Like I had way more strength than I usually do.
我还凭空变出了一个钻石
And I made diamondy thing appear out of nowhere,
平常见到钻石我还是很高兴的
which normally I'd be excited about.
切面那么漂亮，而且－
I mean, the facets were just perfect. And the–
瑞瑞！
Rarity!
啊，抱歉。总之钻石把阿杰撞翻然后消失了
Oh, sorry. It knocked Applejack over and then it disappeared!
说到消失，有人看见云宝黛茜没？
Speaking of disappearing, has anybody seen Rainbow Dash?
你怎么做到的？
How did you do that?
我也不知道
I don't know.
我本来是跑去拿安全带
I've started running to get the harness,
结果一下子就跑回城里去了
and the next thing I knew I was practically back in town!
但如果你有某种超速的能力
But if you had some sort of superspeed,
为什么又消失了这么久？
why you were gone for so long?
因为跑远了就不起作用了
Because I lost it when I got far away.
我离营地近一点的时候才有
And then it came back when got close to camp.
这个营地给了我们新的魔法能力
Being at camp is giving us all new magical abilities!
不是大家都有，我就没有
Not all of us has gotten new abilities. I haven't,
不过暮暮－
but Twilight–
也没有
hasn't, either.
看来扯离坎高远一点就不会碰到魔法都是白扯了
So much for my theory that leaving CHS would mean leaving any new magic business behind.
营地里一定有什么原因
Something at the camp must be making this happen.
比如…森界盖娅？
Um, Gaia Everfree?
阿杰！我正找你呢！
Applejack! I was looking for you!
来，我给你带了毛巾和干衣服
Here, I brought you some towels and dry clothes.
这里出什么事了
Uh, what happened in here.
我们也在想呢
We're kinda trying to figure that out.
那不用担心了，我行的！
Well, don't worry about it. I got this!
雏菊姐，我把我的豆包踢到湖里了
Gloriosa, I kicked my beanbag into the lake!
我再给你拿一个
I'll get you another one!
还有我的箭也没有了
And I'm all out of arrows!
别急！新箭马上就有！
Say no more! New arrows coming right up!
总算找到你了！
There you are!
臭钱回来了，要我去应付他吗？
Filthy Rich is back. Do you want me to handle it?
当然不用！我行的！
Absolutely not! I got this!
小蝶，不要叫了！
Fluttershy, enough with the screaming!
不是我叫的
I didn't scream.
也就这次不是
For once.
没人叫啊
Nobody did.
营员们注意！
Attention, campers!
想做孔明灯的同学请到野餐桌这里集合
Anyone who's interested in making floating paper lanterns, please meet us by the picnic tables.
你们怎么想我不知道
I don't know about the rest of y'all,
但是我为这次露营都激动了一个月了
but I've been looking forward to coming here for a month.
不如先不管这个魔法，好好享受营地生活？
Maybe we'll forget about this new magic for a bit and just try to focus on enjoying our time at camp?
我也对给时装秀做的设计也很激动呢
I was also excited about designs I've come up for the camp fashion show.
绳球我还想找个人虐虐啊
And I've barely gotten to whoop anybody in tetherball.
我还是觉得应该搞清楚
I think we should try to figure it out.
但是如果你们都觉得可以放一放……
But if letting it go for now is what the rest of you want...
萍琪，你干嘛呢？
Pinkie Pie, what are you doing?
往我的孔明灯上放棉花糖
Putting marshmallows in my lantern.
然后放的时候我的灯一定又漂亮又好吃
Then when we light them, mine will be beautiful and delicious!
暮暮，你怎么不和别人一起呢
Twilight, why aren't you with everyone else?
余晖说营地里有什么东西给了她们新的魔法能力
Sunset said something at camp is causing the other girls to get new magic.
我觉得是暗夜闪闪
I think it's Midnight Sparkle.
她依然是我的一部分，我能感受到
She's still part of me. I can feel it.
我觉得是她的魔法在传染我的朋友
And I think her magic is infecting my friends.
那我们怎么办？
What are we gonna do?
我也不知道要怎么办
I don't know what I can do.
好了大家！
Okay, everyone!
是时候看你们的孔明灯上天了！
It's time to watch your lanterns fly!
喂，灯笼不错哦
Hey, cool lantern!
我的灯上面画的是我的脸
Mine's my face.
你还好吗
Uh, you okay?
嗯
Mhm.
你今晚有点不对劲啊
You don't seem like yourself tonight.
准备——放！
Ready? And... Go!
没事，现在我能吃了！
Oh well! Now I get to eat it!
果然是又漂亮又好吃
Yep, Beautiful and delicious.
暮暮？
Twilight?
暮暮！
Twilight! Oh
她要到哪里去？
Oh, where is she going?
暮暮？
Twilight?
你在外面干什么？
What are you doing out here?
我们…找了辆出租回家
We're... we're meeting a cab to take us home.
她觉得你要是知道一定会劝住她
She thought you'd talk her out of it.
我确实要
Because I would
暮暮，你不能走
Twilight, you can't leave.
会不会是那个盖娅啊？
You don't think it was the spirit, do you?!
不是，是我
No, it was me.
我觉得是暗夜闪闪
I think it's Midnight Sparkle.
她依然是我的一部分，我能感受到
She's still part of me. I can feel it.
我觉得是她的魔法在传染我的朋友
And I think her magic is infecting my friends.
暮暮，没有什么暗夜闪闪
Twilight, there's no Midnight Sparkle,
只有你而已
there's only you.
你怎么知道我在想什么？
How did you know what I was thinking?
我碰到了你的手，然后就看见画面了
When I touched your hand, I can see things.
我明白了你为什么要走
I can understand why you were leaving.
我的新魔法！
My new magic!
这就是我的新魔法能力！
This is my new magic!
真的太棒了！
This is incredible!
不棒，现在我连你也传染到了
No, it's not. I'm infecting you now!
暮暮，你不要老是把这当成坏事看
Twilight, you have to stop looking at this as a bad thing.
说得倒容易
Easy for you to say.
魔法把你变成了漂亮的魔法少女
Magic turned you into something beautiful.
可我上次用的时候却变成了一个怪物
The last time I tried to use it, it turned me into a monster.
我怕这样的事还会发生
I'm just so afraid it's gonna happen again.
是，上次是好的，但我也曾被魔法变成一个怪物过
Yes, last time  I turned into something amazing, but I've let magic turn me into a monster, too.
所以要说如果有谁能理解你现在的感受
So if anyone understands what you're going through,
非我莫属
it's me.
暮暮，我能帮你
I can help you, Twilight.
我们的朋友们也都会支持你
And the rest of our friends can be there for you, too.
只要你不离开
But not if you run away.
我留下吧
I'll stay.
我还是觉得我最近不要靠我的朋友太近了
I still don't think it's a good idea for me to be near the rest of our friends right now.
等这事弄清楚了再说
Not until we know why this is happening.
行
Understood.
什么声音
What was that?!
等等，暮暮？
Oh, wait. Twilight?
木杉？还好是你！
Timber? I'm so glad it's just you!
你跑这来干什么？
Wait, what are you doing out here?
还带着斧子
With an axe.
我在砍木柴
I was chopping down firewood.
半夜出来砍？
In the middle of a night?
明天的营火还要用
We needed more for tomorrow night's campfire.
如果我不半夜砍好的话
And if I didn't take care of it tonight,
雏菊就又会跑出来背锅了
it would be one more thing Gloriosa would add to her list.
我行的
I've got this!
那你们呢？
What about you two?
大半夜跑到森林里来干什么
啊
Oh
我梦游来着
I was sleepwalking.
暮暮刚刚找到我正想把我带回去
Twilight found me and was bringing me back to camp.
嗯嗯
Mhm.
来吧，我送你们回去
Come on, I'll walk you guys back.
免得你们见到森灵盖娅！
I'll protect you from Gaia Everfree!
森灵！
Everfree!
去去去，你就是在编出这个故事好在营火边来吓我们的
Come on, that's obviously just a spooky story you made up to tell around the campfire.
没有，是真的哦
Oh, no. It's legit.
你怎么解释码头边发生的事？
How else would you explain what happened at the docks?
还有地震的时候？
And that weird thing when the earth shook?
不说了，回营地有条近路
Uh, come on, I know a shortcut back to the tents.
还真的？我想我知道森灵盖娅是怎么来的了
Legit, huh? I think we just found our Gaia Everfree.
可是他为啥要费这么大劲装神弄鬼呢？
But why would he work so hard to make us think she was real?
他不是说过想让姐姐卖掉营地吗？
You heard what he said about wishing his sister would sell this camp.
如果没人敢来
If nobody wants to come here,
因为这里有一个坏脾气的上古神灵
because it's home to some angry ancient nature spirit,
那不想卖也要卖了
it sure would help his cause.
我们得给暮暮说
We should tell Twilight.
不着急
Not yet.
她现在压力已经很大了
She's obviously going on through a lot right now.
所以我们先要完全确认了
We should probably be a hundred percent sure
再跟她说人家的对象其实是想要毁掉大家营地生活的混蛋
before we tell her the guy she likes is a jerk who's trying to run everybody out of camp.
瑞瑞，你不来帮把手吗？
Uh, you gonna give us a hand here, Rarity?
我也想啊
Oh, I'd love to,
但是我真得先把给时装秀用的披风缝好
but I really need to get the stitching on this poncho done before it's going to make it into the camp fashion show.
不是我催你们
Not to haste you two with moving.
这样修T台要修到猴年马月去了
don't know that the runway will ever be finished.
码头是我们的营地礼物，一定要修好
The dock is our gift to the camp and it's gonna get finished.
前提是云宝能快点把木头送过来
That is if Rainbow Dash would hurry up and bring me more wood.
我不敢快啊！
Oh, I can't go any faster!
才不要又撞到树林里去了
I don't want to end up in the woods again.
别傻了
Don't be silly.
你还说我？
Really?
我确实说过要把魔法的事情放一放
I know I said we should try to forget all about this new magic business,
但是放不下啊
but I can't.
要是把板子敲碎了怎么办？
What if I hammer the board into splinters?
靠，钉子没了
Aw, shoot! I'm out of nails.
拿去！
Oh, here you go!
萍琪，不要！
Pinkie, no!
诶？
What?
哦你们是怕钉子要跟闪粉一样爆炸？
Oh, did you think the nails would explode like the sprinkles?
还好没有呢，是吧？
Glad that didn't happen, huh?
抱歉各位，我不是故意的
Sorry, girls. I didn't mean to.
我不知道怎么控制
And I don't know how to control this.
没事
It's okay.
我们也不知道
Oh, none of us do.
所以不能再装瞎子了
Which is why we shouldn't pretend this isn't happening.
你也有了？
Do you have it now, too?
昨晚开始的
It started last night.
我碰到别人的时候就能感受到别人的情绪和记忆
When I touch people, it's like I can feel what they're feeling and see their memories.
厉害了我的姐！给我试试！
Oooh, fancy! Try me, try me!
诶，好玩！
Ooh, taffy!
原来如此
That explains so much.
对啊
Yep.
大家，即便不合时宜
Girls, we can't just brush these powers aside,
这样的能力不能不理
because it doesn't seem like the ideal time to get them.
万一它们能帮我们一把呢？
What if it turns out that they could actually make things better?
你会魔法
So you have magic
这并没有那么棒
And it's not that great
但当它找上门的时候
But when it found you
你知道那就是命运
You know it was fate
也许现在似乎有些可怕
And it might seem scary now
但它也能很精彩
But it can be wonderful, too
那么，让我们来拥抱魔法吧
So, how about we embrace the magic
让魔法成为你的一部分
And make the magic part of you
用上一点点魔法
You take a little dash of magic
让它发光发热
And you let it ignite
将它们稍稍融合
Mix things up a little bit
事情会开始转好
And it might start to go right
在短短五秒之中
In just five seconds flat
故事如何改变
How the story has changed
都只是因为你已经拥抱了魔法
All cause now you've embraced the magic
一切都在变好
And it just got better in every way
我说，拥抱魔法吧
I say embrace the magic
不要再抗拒，尽情释放吧
No more holding back, just let it out
如果你能使用魔法
If you can take the magic
多了解一些魔法所能做到的
And learn a little more what it can do
一旦魔法成了你的一部分
Once the magic is part of you
阻挡你前行的障碍
What's standing in your way
有何是你当前无法破除的呢
That you can't move today?
你拥有了内在的力量
You've got the strength in you
去实现你的梦想
To make your dreams come true
不必再闭锁你自己
No need to shield yourself
从有益的魔法
From the magic that can help
保护自己免受任何
Protect from any harm
潜在的伤害
That might come
你会魔法
So you have magic
这并没有那么棒
And it's not that great
但当它找上门的时候
But when it found you
你知道那就是命运
You know it was fate
所以，若仔细倾听
So, if you listen close
你可能会交上一个新朋友
You might make a new friend
我们齐心协力 定能成功
And together we can make it!
我说，拥抱魔法吧
I say embrace the magic
不要再抗拒，尽情释放吧
No more holding back, just let it out
如果你能使用魔法
If you can take the magic
多了解一些魔法所能做到的
And learn a little more what it can do
一旦魔法成为你的一部分
Once the magic is part of you
Once the magic is part of yoooou
一旦魔法成为你的一部分
Once the magic is part of you
好吧，刚刚确实很酷炫
Okay, that was pretty awesome!
再看看我们的成果
And look what you managed to accomplish!
求你啦
Please
我们能现在就在这里做一次时装秀彩排吗？
can we do a run-through for the fashion show on it right this minute?
可是你的披风都没缝好
Thought you weren't finished with the stitching on your poncho.
现在缝好了
I am now.
你们先搞吧，我要去找暮暮
Get started without me. I've got to find Twilight.
她看到我们的成果说不定
Seeing what we've been able to do here might
她也就拥抱自己的新魔法了
make her embrace the new magic, too!
不是说她有啊
Uh, not that she has any.
我真希望你没给她们讲这个蠢故事
I just wish you didn't tell them that ridiculous story!
你这样子太过了！要学会放手！
Ah, this is all too much for you! You have to let it go!
我就知道！他想卖掉营地！
I knew it! He wants her to get rid of the camp!
余晖烁烁？你在门后面干什么呢？
Sunset Shimmer? What were you doing behind that door?
啥？没干什么啊
What? Um, nothing.
我－那个－耳环掉了
I, um, lost an earring.
啊，找到了
Uh, there it is!
那个，正好碰到你
Hey, listen. I'm glad I ran into you.
我很想谢谢你
I really wanted to thank you.
谢什么？
For what?
谢你对我情感上的开导
Huh, for the tough love.
就是说要我放弃暮暮的事情
Telling me I should get over Twilight.
对我帮助很大
I needed to hear that.
啊，不客气
Sure, no problem.
你有什么心事吗？
Is something wrong?
啥？没事啊？
别装了，余晖
Come on, Sunset.
你以前是我女朋友
We used to date.
你开不开心我看得出来
I know when something's bothering you.
好吧，是这样的
Okay, here's the deal.
我一个朋友喜欢上了另一个人
My friend really likes someone,
但是我觉得那个人和我朋友心里想的不一样
but I don't think that someone isn't who she thinks they are.
我怕告诉了她我的想法会让她心烦
I don't wanna upset my friend by telling what I think,
但我又想保护她
because I also want to protect her,
如果事情真如我所想的话
because if what I think is happening is really happening,
她还是得知道
then she deserves to know.
你懂吧？
You know?
不懂
No.
但是我知道有你这样的朋友替人分忧
But what I do know is that your friend is lucky to have someone like you
你的朋友是相当幸运
to look out for her.
真的？
Yeah.
Really?
是啊
当初我们一起的时候你还不是这样呢
You know, you've changed a lot since we went out.
现在的你…更好了
You're so much... nicer.
谢了，真高兴你看出来了
Thanks. I'm glad you noticed.
那个，也许我们能重新开始…从朋友做起？
Uh, look, maybe you and me... We could start over as... friends.
嗯嗯，可以
Uh, uh, sounds great.
我先走了
I gotta go!
嗯，那也行！
Cool, yeah!
我也觉得现在重新开始太早了
I want to start over later, too!
唉
Hah.
靠！他绝对在搞事
Ah, shoot! He's definitely up to something!
是余晖。她说要到采石场去见他
It's Sunset. She says to meet her by the rock quarry.
不是说不让去那边吗
I thought we weren't supposed to hike out that far.
她说很重要
She says it's important!
那是什么？
What is that?
出什么事了？
What's going on down there?
我觉得是森灵盖娅
I think it's Gaia Everfree.
或者说是某个希望我们这么想的人
Or rather someone who wants us to think she's back.
走！
C'mon!
这里真漂亮
This place is beautiful.
这里有马国的魔法
There's Equestrian magic here.
我…我感受得到
I can... I can feel it.
等等，我还以为魔法生物什么都是木杉搞出来的
Wait. I thought that Timber was just faking there was magical nature creature.
你的意思是真的有？
Are you saying it's real?
木杉？他怎么又和这事扯上关系的？
Timber? What does he have to do with any of this?
没关系，都是我干的
Nothing. It's all me.
雏菊？可是……木杉
Gloriosa? But... Timber.
我还以为是他想让大家觉得森灵盖娅回来了
I was sure he was the one trying to make it seem like Gaia Everfree was back.
原来是你想吓跑大家？
It was you who was trying to scare everyone away?
我可不想吓跑森灵营地的任何一个人
I would never try scare anyone away from Camp Everfree.
唉哟，看来你贷款还慢了，雏菊啊
My, my. You fell behind on your payments, Gloriosa.
现在地是我的了
I own the land now.
求你了
Please,
这里是我曾祖父母建的
my great grandparents founded this place.
家里一代一代传下来的
It's been in our family for generations!
你不能把营地推掉
You have to let the camp stay!
不修个水疗度假村然后让我赚得盆满钵满？
Instead of turning it into a spa resort that will line my pockets with more money than this camp ever could?
才不干呢
I don't think so.
求你了！我－我－我－再给我一点时间吧！
Please! I-I-I-I just need a little more time!
也行，这个月底为限
Fine. I'll give you 'til the end of the month. Hmph.
我该怎么办？
What will I do?
你不了解这些东西
You don't know what those things are!
但是我知道它们能做些什么！
But I know what they can do!
我一直有练习！
I've been practicing!
现在它们的力量已经为我所用了！
I can control their power now!
你又不能确定！
You don't know that for sure!
我们的营地都要没了！
This is our camp and it's being taken away!
如果这是我们在这里度过的最后一周
If this has to be our last week here, I
那我就要不惜一切代价办好这最后一次
I'm going to use whatever it takes to make it count!
你到处都在用魔法
You were using magic all over the place!
我总得跟他们说点什么幌子吧？
I had to tell them something to cover for you!
你还希望我怎么办？
What did you want me to do?
我真希望你没给她们讲这个蠢故事
I just wish you didn't tell them that ridiculous story!
你这样子太过了！要学会放手！
Ah, this is all too much for you! You have to let it go!
木杉说的放手不是放弃营地
Timber wasn't talking about letting go of the camp.
是说要你放弃这些魔法晶簇
He was talking about you letting go of the magical geodes!
你一直试着办好这周的野营
All those things you were doing to make this week the best week ever,
但是你一用魔法就又会出现新的问题
every time you used magic to do them, you caused another problem somewhere else!
木杉是……在为你打掩护！
Timber was... covering for you!
你怎么知道我在用这些晶簇？
How do you know what I was doing with the geodes?
你怎么知道魔法的事情的？
How do you know about the magic?
我能读心，因为我也有魔法
I can see things. Feel things. Because I have magic, too
而且她也有，我们的朋友们都有
And so does she. And so do our friends.
雏菊，木杉没说错
Gloriosa, Timber wasn't wrong.
也许你不应该再用魔法了
Maybe you should stop using magic?
走火入魔很危险的
Too much of it can be dangerous if you can't control it!
我行的！
Oh, I got this!
我要用魔法拯救我的营地
And I'm going to use it to save my camp.
现在我只是需要更多力量！
I just need more power!
不要！
No!
抱歉了，两位
Sorry, girls.
我清楚自己要做什么
I know what I need to do.
不过我想你们还不懂而已
But I feel like we're not on the same page.
那么……
So...
雏菊！
Gloriosa!
不要！
No!
暮暮和余晖呢？
Where are Twilight and Sunset?
她们要错过我们的彩排了
Oh, they're missing our dress rehearsal.
还是不等她们了
I suppose we can get started without them.
准备好就开始吧！
Whenever you're ready!
都说过你会喜欢了
told you you'd like it.
我看…还行吧
It's alright... I guess.
野营完了我就可以拿走了，对吗？
I get to keep it after camp, though, right?
她看起来…变了！
She looks... different.
是啊，她看起来…长高了
Yeah. She looks... taller.
这只是皮毛而已
This is only a preview.
正式出演的时候还有整整一队要上呢
I've got another entire line I'll debut at the real thing.
你把音乐停了干－
Why did you stop the–
我的天啊
Oh my goodness!
营员们，注意！
Attention, campers!
是森灵盖娅
It's Gaia Everfree!
她是真的！
She's real!
我们完蛋啦！
We're doomed!
雏菊？！你在干什么？！
Gloriosa?! What are you doing?!
那是雏菊？是我秀逗了还是她是飞在空中的？
That's Gloriosa? Am I going crazy or her feet are not touching the ground?
好口怕！
Freaky-deaky!
我有件事要说！
I have an announcement to make!
臭钱想要让这周变成最后一届露营
Filthy Rich wants this to be the last session of Camp Everfree.
但是不要担心，我行的！
But don't worry, I got this!
靠！我们才修好的！
Oh, come on! We literally just finished building that!
守候于此天昏黑
I have waited for the day
誓要驱逐贪狼回
To send this greedy wolf away
神秘的魔法助我为神
Now the magic is my salvation
雄伟缭绕据于我身
Gather close in my protection
定要守护这营地
We will stand for Everfree!
仰望那自然的恩赐，荣美而华丽
Behold the beauty of nature in all its glory
不惧那贪婪之人眉睫翘
No need to fear the vultures at the door
我会守护你 战至最后
Right here you have me to protect you
于荆之壁怒吼
Within these walls of thorns
为森灵地 永不沦落
For Everfree forevermore!
前方的战火燃我眉
They have come into our domain
铁链之下吾土危
Here to seal our camp in chains
但我们守护它代代至深
But we have held it for generations
混乱只不过是须臾之时
This is just a complication
定 要 保卫这营地！
We will stand for Everfree!
相信我 一切不会辜负
Trust in me, this is for your own good
不要颤巍
Don't be afraid
自然伴吾身
Nature is our friend
围绕我们不止美丽繁华
All of this beauty that surrounds us
花朵的美丽 是自卫的伪装
Every lovely bloom designed to defend
来啊 放马都过来！
Let them come! Just let them try!
才不会轻易退下来！
I'm not about to say goodbye!
营地会于此永驻万世
This camp will be here throughout the ages
被世界纪录于广阔历史
Written into the history pages
定要保卫这营地！
We will stand for Everfree!
为什么我们身上老出这种事？
Oh, why do these kind of things always happen to us?
我们要怎么办？
What are we going to do?
跟以往一样！
What we always do!
拯救世界！
Save the day!
唉哟唉哟唉哟
Oh boy, oh boy, oh boy!
一定会超级好玩的！
This is gonna be so much fun!
真希望之前有空做超级英雄的斗篷！
I only wish we had time to make superhero capes!
确实啊！
Oh, me too!
我们的衣服已经够多了！
Duh, enough about our wardrobe!
不能让雏菊姐把大家都困在这里！
We've got to stop Gloriosa from trapping everybody in here!
啊，那个，你们能帮把手－爪子吗？
Um, hi. Do you think you can give us a hand– Um, or paw?
我们真的很需要一条通道
We could really use a way out.
没用！她的魔法太强了！
This isn't working! Her magic is too strong!
干得好，斯派克！
Nice work, Spike!
暮暮，你得用你的魔法了！
Twilight, you have to use your magic!
我觉得我挪不动那么大的东西
I don't think I can lift something that big.
能不能出去帮朋友们就靠你了
It’s our only chance of getting out of here and helping our friends!
为什么要抗拒我？
Why are you fighting me?
我是在拯救我们的营地！
I'm doing this to save our camp!
都是为了你们好啊！
I'm doing this for you!
雏菊姐，我们仔细想想好吗？
Gloriosa, let's just think about this for a moment, shall we?
我确实非常喜欢森灵营地
I mean, I think Camp Everfree is absolutely delightful,
但是要让我放弃每周一次的水疗还是有点难受呢
but I just don't know if I'm quite ready to give up my weekly trips to the spa.
水疗？
To the spa.
水疗？！
TO THE SPA?!
雏菊，不是这么来的！
Gloriosa, this isn't the way!
多谢关心，木杉
I appreciate your concern, Timber,
不过我行的！
BUT I GOT THIS!
你不行啊
Gah. No, you don't!
暮暮，你能再用一下魔法吗？
Twilight, do you think you can use your magic?
我不想用太多了
I don't wanna use too much.
暗夜闪闪可能会乘虚而入
Midnight Sparkle could take over.
暮暮，我们的朋友都在里面呢
Twilight, our friends are in there!
好吧
Okay.
雏菊，你做的事情太疯狂了
Please, Gloriosa. What you're doing is crazy.
你得听我讲啊！
You have to listen to me!
那不是雏菊
That isn't Gloriosa.
暮暮！
Twilight!
余晖！
Sunset!
你们没事！
You're okay!
那不是你姐姐了
That isn't your sister.
那是被马国魔法吞噬之人
It's someone who's been consumed by Equestrian magic.
不管你是谁，快放过我姐姐
Whoever you are, you have to let my sister go!
雏菊，求你了，快回来
Please, Gloriosa, come back!
我需要你！雏菊！
I need you! Gloriosa!
瑞瑞！
Rarity!
我没法一直撑下去的
I can't keep this up forever!
都靠你了，你能用魔法把荆棘撑开
It's up to you. You can use your magic to pull the brambles apart!
不行的，太多了
No. There's too many of them.
消耗的魔力太大，我不行的！
It would take too much magic. I can't!
没有别的办法！你需要拥抱你心中的魔法！
It's the only way! You have to embrace the magic inside you!
要是她趁虚而入怎么办？
What if she takes over?
要是我变成了暗夜闪闪，雪上加霜了怎么办？
What if instead of saving everyone, I'll turn into Midnight Sparkle and only make things worse?
不会这样的！
That won't happen!
我们不会坐视不管
We won't let it.
暮暮！加油！你要强过她！
Come on, Twilight! You have to be stronger than she is!
你永远没法控制我！
You will never control me!
我永远都是你的一部分！
I will always be a part of you!
不要！
Nooo!
暮暮，听我说！
Twilight, listen to me!
你才是主导
You are in charge!
亲爱的，你是光辉，是善良之力
You are a light, darling! A force for good!
你能把黑恶势力打个屁滚尿流！
Yeah! You can kick the darkness’s butt!
我们都支持你，暮暮！
We're here for you, Twilight!
不论怎样我们都不会离开你
And we'll be here no matter what!
我们相信你
We believe in you!
你不是暗夜闪闪
You are not Midnight Sparkle!
不！我是暮光闪闪！
No! I am Twilight Sparkle!
我的心中魔法，是友谊的魔法！
And the magic I carry inside me is the magic of friendship!
不！不要！
No! Stop!
雏菊？
Gloriosa?
出…出什么事了？
What... What happened?
没事了，一切都会好的
It's okay. It's gonna be okay.
你成功了！
You did it!
噢，项链不错
Oh, nice bling.
这…这是啥子啊？
What... What are these?
我也不清楚，但它们与我们之间显然有某种联系
I'm not sure. But clearly we have some kind of connection to them.
究竟是什么我也不怎么在乎了
I almost don't care what they are.
它们真漂亮
They are gorgeous!
而且和营地时装秀的衣服肯定很配！
And will totally go with the other collection I was working on for the camp fashion show!
不过恐怕办不成了，不是吗？
That's probably cancelled, isn’t' it?
我真是对不起大家
I am so sorry.
我只是想让这周成为最棒的野营周
I only wanted this to be the best week Camp Everfree has ever had.
可是却办成了最糟糕的
Then instead I've made it the worst.
也许把营地给臭钱确实是最好的选择吧
Maybe it's for the best that I'm losing the camp to Filthy Rich.
不是的
No, it's not.
这个营地对太多的人有太多的意义了
This camp has meant so much to so many people,
包括我和我妹妹
my sister and me included.
我们把学生送过来也是这个原因
Why do you think we wanted our students to come here?
不能让臭钱把这块地占了
We can't let Filthy Rich take this place away!
如果营地对你们这么有意义，那么对这么多年来的那么多营员也是如此吧
If camp meant so much to you two, maybe it meant as much to the other campers who came here in years past?
也许可以让他们来拯救这里
And maybe we can get them to help save it!
像是筹资活动那种？
Oh, like a fundraiser?
或者说晚会？
Or a ball?!
我们的乐队可以去表演！
Our band can play!
我可以帮忙给这个活动写首新歌！
I can help writing a new song just for the occasion!
这些想法都很好，可是我们要在哪开呢？
Those are all good ideas, but where would we hold it?
在那个水晶洞里就很好！
We can hold it in the crystal cave!
水晶晚会！
A crystal ball!
我去定了！
I'm on it!
大家这么热情我很高兴，真的
I admire everyone's enthusiasm, really, I do,
但我－我不知道明天之内能不能筹划好和把请帖发好
but I-I just don't know how we're going to plan a ball by tomorrow and invite everyone.
我们行的
We got this!
我曾认为 命运 已 注 定
I used to think that stories were just that
铁了心 再无 变 革 的 余 地
Set in stone, concrete as a fact
我那时 不知悉
It didn't dawn on me
我会 创 造 这 奇 迹
That I could change history
现在我要谱写 自 己 的 篇 章
Now I know I'm writing my own song
拼搏直奔 理 想 的 远 方
Fight my way to the ending that I want
那一路的荆棘
I'll turn a tragedy
会 化 为 我 不 竭 动 力
Into a epic fantasy
嘿！ 嘿！ 嘿！
Hey! Hey! Hey!
你就是那Hero（Hero）呦~
You can be a hero (hero) too
哦-哦-哦
Oh-oh-oh
手拉手， 因为朋友
Take my hand, I'm here for you
快来 随我 前进
Come away with me
这份传奇由你来决定
Be the legend you are meant to be
你会 明晰
You'll always be
你的 真 谛
Everfree
哦-哦啊-啊哦-哦哇-啊哦-哦哇
Oh, oo-wah, ah-oh, oo-wah, ah-oh, oo-wah
这份传奇由你来决定
To be the legend you are meant to be
哦-哦啊-啊哦-哦哇-啊哦-哦哇
Oh, oo-wah, ah-oh, oo-wah, ah-oh, oo-wah
这份传奇由你来决定
To be the legend you are meant to be
心中恐惧 曾让我迷惘
There was a time when fear would hold me down
如枷锁在地 捆住我脊梁
Cause I let it chain me to the ground
快看天高 我翩翩来
Look at me now, I'm soaring high
在这高处 永远都精彩
It's never boring in the sky
当我明白 我的朋友已在旁
When I know I've got friends on my side
任何难关我们 共 同 去 担 当
Whatever trials I'll take them all in stride
在一起 我们最开怀
Together we will shine so bright
就算夜里 光芒也自在
Radiant brilliance in the night
嘿！ 嘿！ 嘿！
Hey! Hey! Hey!
你就是那Hero（Hero）呦~
You can be a hero (hero) too
哦-哦-哦
Oh-oh-oh
手拉手 因为朋友
Take my hand, I'm here for you
快来 随我 前进
Come away with me
这份传奇由你来决定
Be the legend you are meant to be
你会 明晰
You'll always be
你的 真 谛
Everfree
哦-哦啊-啊哦-哦哇-啊哦-哦哇
Oh, oo-wah, ah-oh, oo-wah, ah-oh, oo-wah
这份传奇由你来决定
To be the legend you are meant to be
哦-哦啊-啊哦-哦哇-啊哦-哦哇
Oh, oo-wah, ah-oh, oo-wah, ah-oh, oo-wah
这份传奇由你来决定
To be the legend you are meant to be!
感谢各位光临
Thank you all so much for coming.
也感谢各位筹集到足够的钱来…
And for helping us raise enough money to...
…拯救森灵营地！
save Camp Everfree!
感谢你们所做的一切
Thank you for everything.
如果之前找你们帮忙就好了
Oh, if I just asked for help in the first place.
不必担心
Heh, don't sweat it,
我们就是干这事的
it's kinda what we do.
不是我吹，
Not to brag or anything,
能保护营员免受Rubus fruticosus之害，我还是很牛的
but it's pretty cool how I saved all those campers from those Rubus fruticosus.
就是黑莓荆棘啦
Blackberry brambles.
这种植物我倒是知道
I'm familiar with the genus,
不过要说是你救了大家我还有点奇怪
it's just a little weird you say you saved the campers.
我还以为是我呢
I thought I saved them.
是啊，但是我在码头边上救了你，你才能救大家
Yeah. But I saved you from falling on the docks, so that you can save the campers.
所以还是算我头上
So technically, it was all me.
能遇见你真是幸事
I'm really glad I met you.
啊噢
Uh-oh.
怎么了？
What?
这么说就是要分别了
That sounds like a goodbye.
我还在想我俩能不能出去玩玩
And here I was hoping we'd still be able to hang out. M
比如吃个晚餐看个电影什么的
Maybe get dinner and catch a movie?
我很乐意啊
Yeah. I'd really like that.
那就好，正期待如此呢
Oh, good! I was hoping that's what this meant.
抱歉，我这边需要木杉一下
sorry. I need to borrow Timber.
有几个赞助人我很希望他见一见
There are some donors I really want him to meet.
是我爸妈的老朋友
They were good friends with mom and dad.
一会跟我跳支舞，好吗？
Save me a dance, okay?
太可爱了
Adorable.
他人挺不错啊
He does seem like a pretty cool guy.
知道还有什么不错吗？
You know what else is cool?
我们日天的超能力！
Our awesome new superpowers!
我发了有四百多张传单，搭好了舞台
I handed out, like, four hundred fliers, set up the stage,
还有时间买披萨！
and still had time to pick up pizza! I
我爱死我的超速了
I love my superspeed!
说到这个，我觉得这些晶簇就是我们超能力的来源
About that. I think the crystals are the source of the superpowers.
你不会要让我们放弃它们吧？
You're not gonna ask us to give them up, are you?
不会
No.
其实啊，我觉得也许这是命中注定的相遇？
In fact, I think maybe we were meant to have them all along?
我也这么想
Me too.
但是我还有件事没懂
There's one thing I'm still wondering about, though.
什么？
What's that?
这个洞里的魔法是哪里来的？
Where did the magic that hit this cave come from?
［片尾曲之后有彩蛋］
第三次一般都有好运
Third time is a charm.
或许是第五次？我数不清了
Or is it fifth? I've lost track.
T台撘好了是真的
All that matters is that the runway is finished.
你是说码头吧？
I think you mean "the dock"?
随你怎么叫啦
Oh, tomahto, tomato.
Let's celebrate!
可以庆祝啦